8/31/13 Shiliang Wang

SHILIANG WANG

3501 St Paul St, Baltimore, MD - 21218, United States +86 443 453 7666
wangshiliang@jhu.edu
https://github.com/wangshilianghit

I am a Master student studied at Johns Hopkins University major in Computer Science. My research interests include machine learning approaches and their applications, Information Retrieval, Web Development and mobile applicataion development. I'm also a big fan in basketball.

Education

JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY 2013 - PRESENT

I'm currently a first year Master student advised by Jason Eisner. I'm currently do some research in Informatical and building a language studying website with others right now.

Print Resume

• **GPA**: 3.8/4.0

Major: Computer Science

HARBIN INSTITUE OF TECHNOLOGY 2008-2012

I has been actively invovled in the reaserch on Machine Intelligence Lab in HIT since 2010. I served as a key member in designing HIT search engine system which clusters users search results into topics. I also researched on Chinese word segmentation. My recent paper "Discriminate Chinese word segmenter with global features and context features" has been published in Advanced Material Research.

GPA: 86.7/100

• Major: Software Engineering

Skills

Programming Languages

C, C++ (more than 4 years of experience)

Python, JAVA (2 years of experience)

JavaScript, C#, Perl (half years of experience)

Web

localhost:3000/#

8/31/13 Shiliang Wang

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, NodeJs, Express, Angular, Sails, JSP

Database Technologies

SQL, **MySQL**, **MongoDB**

Operating System

Linux, Windows

Work History

SEEDS OF EMPOWERMENT OF STANFORD UNIVERSITY

Learning Systems Development Associate 09/2012 - Present

Designed Four Andorid games including Card Game, London Tower, FarmSim, Fire Rescue bearing most of the game development work. These games have been tested and played by children in Indonesia. These games aimed to increase children's ability to display flexibility in the face of chaning schedules of reinforcement, and help them learn the concept of money, micro loans, borrowing moeny, etc.

Internship in Neusoft 07/2010 - 09/2010

As the technical director finished the project of Modern Traffic Monitoring System. This system can recognize the plate number of cars that violate the traffic rules and notify to the police.

Awards and Accomplishments

WON THE FIRST PRICE IN THE GLOBAL SOFTWARE DEVELOP COMPETITION

He tooked part in Stanford summer school and joined the Global Software Develop Competition. Their team won the first price in this competition for a mobile mapping applicator named "IGO". This software aimed to help customers find shops and get the recommendation and promotion information quickly.

RECENET PAPER PUBLISH IN ADVANCED MATERIAL RESEARCH

"Discriminate Chinese Word Segmenter with Global and Context Features", Advanced Material Research, International Symposium on Electronical Engineering and Information Processing, ShenYang, China, May, 2012.>

Mustafa Quilon & Themeforest. All Rights Reserved.

localhost:3000/# 2/2